# **Deirdre Connolly**

Email: durumcrustulum at gmail dot com I Download

Software engineer with experience in all levels of the web application stack, specifically interested in creating highly performant front end experiences built on elegant APIs. Passionate about tools and automation that make developers more productive.



#### Education

# **Massachusetts Institute of Technology**

2004 - 2008

SB - Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

#### Skills

### Languages + Frameworks

Python, JavaScript, NodeJS, jQuery, CanJS/JSMVC, Coffeescript, Backbone.js, SASS/CSS, AngularJS, Java, Jersey, Guice, Spring

#### **Tools**

Linux/Unix, git, svn, perforce, grunt, puppet, AWS, MySQL, redis, memcached

## Experience

## **Software Engineer** Akamai Technologies | Feb 2013 - Present

- Worked on Property Manager, a web application enabling customers to configure complex Akamai Edge Network products without support. Front end engineering work with JSMVC/CanJS, Sass, and backend work usingJersey/JAX-RS/JAX-B and Spring
- Contributed to continuous integration and deployment infrastructure, moving the team codebase from Perforce to git hosted by Atlassian Stash and builds/deploys with Jenkins, now being rolled out across the organization
- Drove improvements in dev tooling and automation, including new static dev environment with Grunt and NodeJS w/ Express with automated i18n generation, unit tests, style and script compilation on the fly

## **Product Developer**

- Django+Javascript front ends such as the platform dashboard, inapp alerts, customer on-boarding experiences, product settings, and data migration workflows
- Wrote multiple python REST clients for internal user, account, and product gating services

## **DevOps Engineer**

HubSpot | Aug 2011 - Feb 2012

- Internal deploy tooling and infrastructure, weaving together custom Django interfaces, python scripts, AWS automation, and Jenkins continuous integration
- Replaced local deploy script with Django webapp to enable nosetup, one-click build deploys, using Celery jobs and later Jenkins tasks

# Software Engineer in Test HubSpot | April 2010 - Aug 2011

- Automated browser and REST API testing with python and selenium
- Team designed new testing frameworks based on nose.

# **Technical Specialist** Intersystems | July 2008 - Feb 2010

- Supported application developers utilizing the Caché postrelational database platform, language bindings and frameworks
- Debugged and instructed use of .NET, Java, Perl and Python bindings, CSP web application framework setup and operation

#### Extracurriculars

#### Boston Women's Rugby Football Chub Jan 2012 - Present

- Designed new responsive <u>www.bwrfc.com</u> wordpress template, set up Google Analytics, lead tracking, optimized content
- Migrated organization to Google Apps, Google Checkout, and introduced Square usage for IRL events

Competitive powerlifting, corgis

References

Available on request